firehow.com 2014-06-25

# FireHow Privacy Policy | Firehow | FireHow.com

Effective: November 13, 2008

Updated January 1, 2012  

FireHow (“We,” “Us,” “FireHow.com,” “FireHow LLC,” “Website,” or “Site”) is very committed to protecting the privacy of all users while providing a safe experience for all visitors and writers. FireHow is a “how to” article website in which registered users can post as many articles as they wish which include step by step instructions about how to do a particular task. All users and visitors have access to all articles posted by FireHow or any of its users. 

Our Privacy Policy applies to any and all information collected online through the FireHow website. By signing up and providing us with your information you agree to this Privacy Policy, our Terms of Use, and WPP Terms of Use.

Information Gathering: FireHow collects information through our website when you register with our website. Collecting your information helps us run our daily business operations and submit the necessary tax information on your behalf if you make over a certain amount of money per year. The information is collected during registration and/or when signing up for sweepstakes and/or contests our website may host.

When signing up for a profile on our website you will be prompted to provide a username, birthday, email address, first name, last name, gender, full address, and password. To register you must agree to the Terms of Use and Privacy Policy. 

When joining the Writer’s Payment Plan (WPP) at FireHow you are choosing to write articles for an opportunity to earn money. To join the WPP you must also agree to the WPP Terms of Use and fill out the required tax forms which ask for your information that we have to collect to fulfill our tax reporting responsibilities. For tax reporting, we need your name (business name, if applicable and necessary), social security number or employer identification number (if applicable), country of residence, and your full address.

By joining FireHow, you agree to provide FireHow with accurate and updated information about yourself when going through the registration process. Information must be updated immediately, upon changing, anytime after the registration process. If the information you have provided is false or inaccurate, we have the right to suspend your account permanently or until such information is corrected.

Using your email address, FireHow may periodically send newsletters or website updates. We may email you FireHow articles of the day and/or articles of the week/month. We may extend offers to users, on behalf of our partners or a third party, about a particular product of service that may be of interest to you, but we will never give out ANY of your personal information without your permission.

Demographic reports may be made for our advertisers so we can work more closely with them to provide the most valuable content and offers to our users. Personal information will never be included in these reports.

We reserve all rights to use your information without notice as needed to satisfy any law or legal request. This helps protect the integrity our FireHow while also protecting users and visitors.

Always remember that any information provided in your public profile can be viewed by visitors and other members. It is a good idea to exclude phone numbers, your address, and email. If you post personal information online, you may receive unsolicited messages from others, which FireHow has no control over this use of your personal information.

FireHow will also periodically run sweepstakes where users and visitors can enter their information to have a chance to win money, gift cards, and/or a wide array of prizes. We will never share your personal information with anyone. We will not spam you using your email. To enter for a sweepstakes we may collect a variety of information such as, but not limited to, your name, phone number, email address, mailing address, your age, gender, education level, number of children you have, referring site, and your general interests. We will give you the option to signup for our newsletter which you may opt out of at anytime. We may contact you if you are the winner of the sweepstakes and you cannot opt out of such a contact. If you plan on entering any of our sweepstakes please read our Participation Terms. You must agree to our Terms, Privacy Policy, and Participation Terms to participate in any sweepstakes.

Cookies: FireHow uses “cookies” which allows us to obtain certain kinds of information when you visit our website. Cookies allow us to obtain information such as the time and date that you visited our site along with which pages you have visited. Cookies allow us to collect your computers IP address, the host you use to access the internet and domain name. Personally identifiable information are not contained on Cookies and therefore do not identify you personally. Some cookies may have some profile information about you and/or demographic information but never any personally identifiable information about you. You have the option to disable Cookies on your browser although some features may not be accessible on our website. FireHow may place a Cookie on your browser. This lets FireHow recognize you as an anonymous and unique user. Some companies who place advertisements on our website may use Cookies on our website and their own website. We have no control over the other companies and their Cookies. If you click on any link or advertisement, the linked or advertising company may place a Cookie on your computer. We have no control over another company. You should always read any Privacy Policy and/or Terms of Use they have on their website.

Third-party advertising companies use cookies to serve ads on FireHow.

Our main third-party advertising company, Google, use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users of FireHow based on users visits to FireHow and other websites on the internet. Users can opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting:

http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html

To find out more about the DART cookie, visit: 

http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/faq.aspx

Your Information & Information Sharing: At any time a user can change, delete, or correct any personal information they provided to FireHow. Users can opt out from any newsletters or promotional emails at any time. Your information is secure. To maintain a high level of security, we conduct various security measures such as external audits and internal reviews. Even though we conduct various security measures, we do not guarantee security. You assume all risk of any security breaches. You agree to do everything you can to promote security. If you desire a higher level of security, then you agree to not enter information on the FireHow website. Never provide sensitive information in emails and always remember to log off when finished using the FireHow website.

Demographic information may be shared with advertisers but never any personal and identifiable information. FireHow shares information when we are required to comply with law and/or follow any legal process. FireHow will comply with any laws and do whatever it takes to protect the rights of FireHow users. FireHow may hire third parties to help prepare tax forms and filings. We may hire a third party to prepare federal, state, and local tax forms along with 1099 forms for any user who is paid over $10 in a calendar year. Third party assistance may be required for customer service, article/content editing, analyzing data, and content monitoring. In growing and expanding our business, we may sell our company, sell certain parts, sell certain assets, and/or merge with another company. In such an event, any and all user information may be one of the transferred assets, whether it is personally identifiable or not.

Advertisements and Links: FireHow is not responsible for any other websites privacy practices. Any advertisements on our website may contain links to another website which is in no way affiliated with FireHow. In such instances, you should always read the linked websites privacy policies and terms of use to understand what such site may use collected personal information for. This privacy statement only applies to the information collected on FireHow.

FireHow uses third-party advertising companies to provide our website with ads when you visit our website. These third-party advertising companies may use information (not including your email address, address, telephone number, or name) about your visits to FireHow and other websites in order to place and provide advertisements about services and goods of interest to you.

Conditions of Use and Changes: If you do not agree with this Privacy Policy, our Terms of Use, or the ways in which we will use and disclose your information then please do not use FireHow. In such instances, not only should you not use FireHow, you should not provide us any information or post any content on the website. FireHow reserves all rights to send you communications necessary for everyday business operations without you having the ability to opt out or unsubscribe.

FireHow will change and/or update this Privacy Policy as much as needed to continually keep the highest protection for our users. We will also update and modify our Privacy Policy at our sole discretion. We will post such changes immediately and recommend you review our Privacy Policy every time you access our website. We assume you review our Privacy Policy on a regular basis to check for changes and/or modifications.

If you choose to visit FireHow.com, any dispute over your privacy is subject to this Policy and our Terms of Use. This includes limitations on damages and application of the law of the State of Michigan. If you have any issues of concerns about privacy at FireHow, please fill out the Contact Us form or email [support@FireHow.com](mailto:support@FireHow.com). We will work hard to resolve any issues or concerns you may have.
